<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Noel Burton-Krahn - Humour</title><link href="http://burton-krahn.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://burton-krahn.com/feeds/humour.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://burton-krahn.com/</id><updated>2006-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Core of Darkness</title><link href="http://burton-krahn.com/core-of-darkness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2006-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Donald Chan</name></author><id>tag:burton-krahn.com,2006-08-11:/core-of-darkness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Coopalpyse Now&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A young Co-op is sent down I-5 to "downsize" Don Knuth because his
methods are unsound. The co-op student is well trained in .Net, XML,
and Design Patterns, and he's sent to off Knuth for his heretical
non-standards-base approach (and specifically, the MMIX-fallacy based
on --gasp-- assembly language!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UVic, shit.  Eight years into my degree, and I'm still trying to get
through calculus.  My girlfriend graduated last year and left me for a
commerce major.  Every semester I spend on this campus I get weaker.
I just wanted one co-op term that wasn't testing or writing
documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At his briefing, the co-op student is handed a listing of an APL
program by the chief architect of the .NET CLR, while the Spec Lead of
the Java Community Process group looks on. An unnamed representative
from W3C is sitting in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: "Are you familiar with this language, son?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: "No sir"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The W3C guy gives the student a significant look)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: "What about Forth?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: "Sir, I have never participated in any projects utilizing these
languages. Furthermore, if I had in fact participated in any such
projects, I would not be at liberty to speak of them at this
time. Sir."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the co-op student is being driven down the I-5 in an SUV, he
reviews Knuth's dossier and ruminates "this guy wrote two volumes of
The Art of Computer Programming, then gave it all up to implement
TeX. Back to coding, at his age? What balls. I tried to write a
validating XML processor when I was 18 and it damn near killed me."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get directions to Knuth, Willard is sent to see Bill "Kernel"
Kiljoy, a former Sun VP, now with Microsoft. Kiljoy is in the process
of reorganizing a software company recently acquired by Microsoft.
Willard meets Kiljoy on-site, where half the programming staff has
been given pink slips and the other half is being indoctrinated in the
Microsoft development style.  Flunkies scurry everywhere, installing
hardware and software, while hapless employees look on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FLUNKY: The network topology's pretty hairy here, sir. Some of it's
old 10 megabit coax. There?s even a 4 megabit token ring. I don't know
where we'll get the bandwidth to set up VoIP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KILJOY: We can get rid of some of these Unix workstations for a start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiljoy yanks an ethernet cable out of the back of a nearby computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAPLESS EMPLOYEE: Hey, that's Charlie's network connection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KILJOY: So what? Charlie won't surf!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new horde of flunkies arrive and begin to install Windows Vista on
all the computers in the office. Kiljoy starts up Visual Studio on a
computer and several minutes later, source code is displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KILJOY: You see that? Do you see that? Hungarian notation, son. No
other coding style in the world looks like that. I love to look at C#
in the morning. You know, one time we migrated some BSD software to
.NET.  When it was all done I reviewed the code. I didn't understand
one line, not one stinkin' expression. It was the style, you know that
verbose COBOL-like style, the whole program. It looked like... like
the Reverse-injected Victory Pattern. (He casts an avuncular glance at
Willard and winks). Some day this software's going to ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the boardroom waiting for Knuth, the VP of Marketing explains
Knuth's brilliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPM: no mantissa. You can't address memory, you can't index into
     process space, with, like you know, floating point numbers. What
     byte do you get with 2.5E-1, 3.75E-1, what are you gonna do when
     you reach the end of allocated storage or something -- that's
     array subscripting, OK?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never leave the cubicle, absolutely goddamn right, unless you're going
all the way.  Knuth left the cubicle, he wrote the whole fucking
program.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>